In this video, we're gonna talk about regular languages which are used to
在这段视频中，我们将谈论常规语言，这些语言用于
specify the lexical structure of programming languages. To briefly review
指定编程语言的词汇结构。简要回顾一下
the lexical structure of a programming language is a set of token classes. And
编程语言的词汇结构是一组令牌类。和
each one of the token classes consists of some set of strings. Now we need a way to
每个令牌类都由某组字符串组成。现在我们需要一种方法
specify which set of strings belongs to each token class and the usual tool or
指定哪组字符串属于每个令牌类和常用工具，或者
doing that is to use regular languages. So in this video we're going to present like
这样做就是使用常规语言。因此在这段视频中，我们将呈现如下内容
regular languages and define what they are and then in subsequent videos we're going
并定义它们是什么，然后在后面的视频中我们将介绍
to look at some examples using them in actual programming languages. To define
来看一些在实际编程语言中使用它们的示例。要定义
the regular languages, we generally use something called regular expressions. And
对于正则语言，我们通常使用一种叫做正则表达式的东西。和
each regular expression team now it's a set. There are two basic regular
每个正则表达式团队现在都是一个集合。有两个基本规则
expressions. If I write the single character C, that's an expression and what
表情。如果我写下单个字符C，那就是一个表达式
at the notes is a language containing one string. Which is the single character C,
音符上有一种包含一个字符串的语言。它是单个字符C，
okay, That's one basic form so for any single character I get a language with a
好的，这是一种基本形式，所以对于任何单个字符，我都会得到一种带有
one string language with just and then the only string is that character. Another
一种字符串语言，带有Just，然后唯一的字符串是该字符。另一个
basic building block of regular languages is the regular expression epsilon which is
构建正则语言的基础挡路是正则表达式ε，它是
the language. That contains again just a single string, this time the empty string.
语言。它同样只包含单个字符串，这次是空字符串。
And, one thing that's important to keep in mind is that epsilon is not the empty
而且，有一件重要的事情要记住，ε不是空洞的
language, okay? So this is not correspond to the empty string and the empty set of
注意用语，好吗？因此，这与空字符串和空集
strings. It is a language that has a single string namely the empty string.
弦。它是一种只有一个字符串的语言，即空字符串。
Besides the two base regular expressions, there are three compound regular
除了两个基本正则表达式之外，还有三个复合正则表达式
expressions and we'll just go through them here in order. The first is a + b which
表达式，我们将在这里按顺序介绍它们。第一个是a+b，它
corresponds to the union of the languages a and b. So this would be the set a such
对应于语言a和b的并集。所以这将是集合a这样
that a is in the language of big A, little a is in the language of big A union,
A是大A的语言，小A是大A联盟的语言，
little b such that b is in the language of little b so just the union of the two sets
小b，这样b就是小b的语言，所以就是两个集合的并集。
of strings. Concatenation is like string concatenation. So if I have two languages,
一串弦。连接类似于字符串连接。所以如果我有两种语言，
a and b, or two regula r expressions, a and b, then, the concatenation of a and b
a和b，或两个正则表达式a和b，然后是a和b的连接。
Is equal to all of the strings. Little a concatenate with little b where a is drawn
等于所有字符串。小a与小b连接在a所在的位置
from the language big A and little b is drawn from the language big B. And so this
“大A”和“小B”是从“大B”的语言中提取出来的，所以这就是“大B”。
is cross sporadic operation. Choose a string from a. Choose a string from
是交叉零星行动。从中选择字符串。从中选择字符串
capital B and then combine, put them together with the string from a first and
大写B，然后组合，把它们放在一起的字符串从第一个和
choosing strings at all possible ways from all possible combined strings and that's
从所有可能的组合字符串中以所有可能的方式选择字符串，这就是
the language a concatenated with b. And finally there's a kind of looping
语言a和b连接在一起，最后有一种循环
[inaudible]. This is pronounced a star or is called the Kleene iteration and, or the
[听不见]。这发音为一颗星，或称为Kleene迭代，或
Kleene closure. And a star is equal to the union. For i greater than = zero of a to
克莱恩闭合。一颗星等于联盟。对于i大于=0的a到
the i, a to the i-th power. What's that mean? Well, a to the i-th power is just a
i，a的i次方。那是什么意思？嗯，a的i次方只是一个
to concatenated with itself By times. So this is, [inaudible]. And note that
通过时间与自己连接起来。所以这是，[听不见]。请注意，
because i can be = zero, one of the possibilities here is a to the zero, so a
因为i可以=0，这里的一种可能性是a到0，所以a
concatenate with itself zero times and what is that, well that's the language
与自身连接零次，那是什么，好吧，这就是语言
epsilon. So that's the language contain the empty string. So the empty string is
埃普西隆。这就是包含空字符串的语言。因此，空字符串是
always an element of a star. To summarize the last couple of slides the regular
永远是明星的元素。总结一下最后几张幻灯片
expressions over some alphabet sigma. The smallest of that expressions that include
一些字母符号上的表达式。包括以下表达式中最小表达式
the following. So, let's define it so, the regular expression r are equal to epsilon
以下内容。让我们这样定义它，正则表达式r等于ε
is always a regular expression. Or, another possibility is the single
始终是正则表达式。或者，另一种可能性是单人
character c where c is an element of our alphabet, okay? So this is important the
字符c，其中c是我们字母表中的一个元素，好吗？所以这一点很重要
regular expressions define with respect to some alphabet. So we have to pick a family
正则表达式根据某些字母表定义。所以我们得选一个家庭
of characters that will form the base cases of the regular expression and here,
将形成正则表达式的基本情况的字符，并且在这里，
you know? We have one base regular expression for each character in the
你知道?中的每个字符都有一个基本正则表达式。
alphabet. And then we have the compound expressions. So, another possibility Is
字母表。然后我们有复合表达式。所以，另一种可能性是
that a regular expression is the union of two regular expressions. Another one is
正则表达式是两个正则表达式的并集。另一个是
that the concatenation of two regular expressions. And the last one is that it
两个正则表达式的连接。最后一个就是它
could be the iteration of a regular expre ssion. So these five cases are the set of
可能是正则表达式的迭代。那么这五个案例就是
regular expressions over a given alphabet. Now this syntax here for describing the
给定字母表上的正则表达式。现在，这里的语法用于描述
regular expressions with these vertical bars and these different cases on the
带有这些竖线和这些不同大小写的正则表达式
right hand side in this recursive definition of r, If you haven't seen this
在r的递归定义的右侧，如果您还没有看到这个
before, this is called the grammar. And that's not important for this lecture.
在此之前，这被称为语法。这对这堂课来说并不重要。
It's not what this, this lecture is about but we're talking about grammars when we
这不是这个，这堂课讲的是什么，但是我们谈论的是语法，当我们
get to parsing. Next I'd like to do a few examples of actually building regular
开始解析。接下来，我想做几个实际构建规则的示例
languages, writing the mountain and thinking about what they mean. And as we
语言，写山，思考它们的意思。当我们
said, whenever we're talking about a regular language, we first have to say
说，当我们谈到常规语言时，我们首先要说
what the alphabet is. And so, for these examples let's just use the alphabet zero
字母表是什么。因此，对于这些例子，让我们使用字母表0
and one. So these are going to be languages which consists of strings of 0s
还有一个。所以这些将是由0字符串组成的语言
and 1s. And let's start with a very simple example. Let's think about the language
和1。让我们从一个非常简单的例子开始。让我们来考虑一下语言
one star And what language that to note. So, well, we know the definition of star.
一颗星和要注意的语言。所以，好吧，我们知道恒星的定义。
If you remember, that was the union over i greater than = zero of one to the i. Okay.
如果你们还记得的话，那是i上的和大于=1到i的0，好的。
And what is that equal to? Well, that's just one. Repeated i that's what the
这等于什么呢？嗯，这只是其中之一。我重复了一遍，这就是
concatenation of one to the i means, okay. It means one concatenated with itself i
把1连成I的意思，好的。它的意思是一个与它自己连接起来的东西
and so this is going to be the empty string. That's one concatenated with
所以这将是空字符串。这是一个与之相连的
itself zero followed by one followed by eleven followed by one concatenated with
其本身为0，然后是1，然后是11，然后是与连接的1
itself three followed by one concatenated with itself four followed by one
其本身三接一与自身连接四接一
concatenated with itself any number of times. Okay, And this, and so we can see
与其自身连接了任意次数。好的，还有这个，所以我们可以看到
that this is just equal to all strings Of 1s, All right? Now let's do a second
这正好等于所有1的字符串，好吗？现在让我们做一秒钟
example let's think about the language one. Plus zero concatenated with the
让我们考虑一下语言一。加零，并与
language one, okay? And remember how concatenation works is across products we
语言一，好吗？请记住，串联是如何在我们的产品之间工作的
take every string in the first expression and combining with every string in the
将第一个表达式中的每个字符串与
second expression. So this is going to be equal to the strings a b where a is drawn
第二个表达式。所以这将等于画出a的字符串a
from one + zero and b is drawn from one. All right? And, what can that be when
从1+0开始，b从1开始。好的?而且，那会是什么呢？
there's two traces for a. A could be one or zero and b could be one so in fact this
a有两个轨迹，a可以是1也可以是0，b可以是1，所以实际上这是
is equal to the set one, one and the strings one, one, the second [inaudible]
等于集合一，一和弦一，一，二[听不见]
of the strings one, one and one zero. All right? Let's do another examples, slightly
一，零的弦。好的?让我们再举一个例子，稍微
more complex. Let's build up here to having two iterations in a union so have
更加复杂。让我们在这里构建一个联合中有两个迭代
zero + one and think of about what's that equal to but we've already know what
0+1，想一想这等于什么，但是我们已经知道了
one is equal to. That's equal to all strings of ones and so by analogy zero
一等于。这等于所有的1字符串，所以可以类推为0
must be all strings of zeroes then we take the union of those two things so this is
一定都是零的字符串，然后我们取这两个东西的和，所以这是
actually really easy to write out. Let's write them out in this notation so we have
实际上很容易写出来。我们用这个符号把它们写出来，这样我们就有了
zero to the i, for i again equal to zero, okay. That's zero union with. One to the
从零到i，因为i再次等于0，好的。这是零结合。一对一
i or greater than = zero. That's the strings of all one. So there's a set at
i或大于等于零。那是所有人的主线。所以有一个场景设在
this expression to nodes. And for our last example, let's think about zero + one.
将此表达式转换为节点。对于我们的最后一个例子，让我们考虑一下0+1。
Now, that iterated. Okay? So, we put the star around the union of the two
现在，这又重复了一遍。好吧?所以，我们把星星放在两者的结合处
individual character instead of having the star on each character individually in
单个字符，而不是将星号分别放在
taking the union of the two things. So what is the, what is this expression equal
把这两样东西结合起来。那么，这个表达式等于什么呢？
to? Well, let's work with the definition of star. So, we know. That this is the
致？好，让我们来研究一下明星的定义。所以，我们知道。这就是
union over i greater than or equal to zero of zero + one to the i. And what does that
与i的并大于或等于0的0+1到i，这是什么意思？
look like, well, that looks like first of all, there's the empty string, right? And
看起来，嗯，这看起来像是，首先，有一个空字符串，对吗？和
then another string in this language is, is. Excuse me, is drawn from zero + one
那么这种语言中的另一个字符串是，is。打扰一下，是从0+1抽签的
and so this, I shouldn't say another string but another set of strings is the
所以这个，我不应该说另一个字符串，但是另一组字符串是
language zero + one. And then zero + one concatenated with itself, okay? And in
语言0+1。然后0+1和它自己连接起来，好吗？以及在
general, is going to be zero + one concatenated by itself i times. Now what
一般情况下，将会是0+1自身串联的i倍。现在怎么办？
does that mean? That means that every position, if we have a string of length i,
那是不是意味着？这意味着每个位置，如果我们有一根长度为i的弦，
at every position we could pick a zero or a one to plug in and this works for any
在每个位置，我们都可以选择0或1来插入，这对任何
length string. This is gonna be true of strings of every length and so in fact
长度字符串。所有长度的字符串都是如此，所以事实上
this language is just going to be all strings Of 0's and 1's. In fact, what that
这门语言将全部是0和1的字符串。事实上，那是什么
means is this, is the cycle effect on our alphabet. Our alphabet that consists of
意思是，这是我们字母表上的循环效应。我们的字母表包括
zero and one and so this is the set of all strings that you can form over the entire
0加1，这是可以在整个上形成的所有字符串的集合
alphabet, And that has a special name when that happens when you have a regular
字母表，它有一个特殊的名字，当你有一个常规的
expression that denotes the set of all strings you can form out of the alphabet,
表示可以从字母表中形成的所有字符串的集合的表达式，
we write that as sigma star, okay? So just meaning that all the strings of the
我们把它写成西格玛之星，好吗？所以我的意思是所有的字符串
alphabet integrated as many times as you like One last point I wanna make on this
字母表按您的喜好集成了多少次，我想就这一点提出最后一点
before we go on here is that there are actually lots of ways to write each of
在我们继续之前，实际上有很多方法来编写每个
these different languages. There's not a unique way to write these. So for example,
这些不同的语言。没有一种独特的方式来写这些。举个例子，
let's just take this language here. The second one that we did, and let me switch
让我们把这种语言放在这里。我们做的第二个，让我换一下
colors. Another alternative way to write this since we know the meaning of it is
颜色。既然我们知道它的意思，另一种写这个词的方式是
these two strings one, one and one zero, I could have written it as one, one. + one
这两个字符串1，1和1，我可以写成1，1。+1
zero and that would mean exactly the same thing. We used two expressions denote
零，那是完全一样的意思。我们用两个表达式表示
exactly the same set similarly with one star, I could write this as one 'lt;i>. + one.'lt;/i>
完全相同的集合与一颗星类似，我可以写成一‘lt；i>.’+1.‘lt；/i>
And cuz this wouldn't change anything. Adding in the single string one wouldn't
因为这不会改变任何事。添加到单个字符串中不会
change anything since one is already included in one'lt;i>. This might be kind of
更改任何内容，因为其中一个已经包含在一个‘lt；i>中。这可能是一种
a'lt;/i> silly way to write that set but it doesn't matter it has a meaning and it means exactly
A‘lt；/i>写那一套很傻，但这无关紧要，它有意义，它的意思就是
the same things as one'lt;i>. The point again is that there is more than one way'lt;/i>
和一个人一样的事情；我>。同样重要的是，有不止一种方法；/i>
to write down the same set to write, to write, you can write multiple regular expressions
要写下同一组写，写，你可以写多个正则表达式
that denote the same set.
表示相同的集合。